

# Tarek Messaoudi

Full Stack Engineer chez Qynapse

FR

+33614669466

tmessaoudi94@gmail.com

fr, Allemand, Anglais, Arabe, Français

# **BACKGROUND**

### **ABOUT**

I'm a full stack web developer who can build apps from the ground up. I've worked mostly at startups so I am used to wearing many hats. I am a very product focused developer who prioritizes user feedback first and foremost. I'm generally very flexible when investigating new roles.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Full Stack Engineer, Qynapse

Nov, 2020 - Present

I mainly contributed to the development of the core product: Qyscore. Key Achievements:

Viewer:

Built a new viewer structure with Cornerstone and React Admin.

Integrated Cypress for end-to-end testing.

Optimized the cache and memory usage mechanism

Report:

Improved PDF generation with Puppeteer and enhanced testing procedures.

Reworked the PDF generation process.

Implemented internationalization with .pot files.

**DIMSE Agent:** 

Maintained the DIMSE agent for efficient and secure data ingestion.

#### Libraries:

Created a normative library for percentiles and z-scores.

Developed microservices for mesh and slice operations.

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Python
- Kubernetes
- React
- Tailwind
- FastApi
- PostgreSQL
- o DICOM

## Full Stack Engineer, ALTER SOLUTIONS

Nov, 2017 - Nov, 2020 3 years

Service Portal

Client: IRT SystemX

Description: Central Dashboard promoting research project webservices

Achivement: Develop the whole Application

Teck Stack:

- NodeJS
- TypeScript (ts-node)
- Express
- REST + GraphQL API
- MongoDB (with Mongoose ORM)
- React JS
- TypeScript ( with create react app)
- Forms: formik, yup, react-select
- o CSS framwork: Tailwind CSS
- o network:swr

**FASTR** 

Client: SFR ALTICE GROUP

Description: Brand-new customer service web app

Achievement:

- Add features (Format, send Mail/SMS, Tray, ...)
- Frontend: Add redux & "core components"
- o Backend: Add "public" APIs & documentation

Tech Stack:

- o Javascript:
- TypeScript
- ReactJS (Class, Hooks),
- Redux,
- o Formsy, ...
- Java 11:
- SpringBoot 2
- Microservices architecture with Kubernetes and Nginx
- MongoDB / Redis

**WEASY LOCATION** 

Client: NEXITY

Description: Brand-new estate rental app

#### Achievement:

- Add business features (Renting sheet delegation, Lease proposal acquittance, Candidate Case creation, ...)
- o Add Azure AD Authentication

Tech Stack:

- React Js, Redux, redux-form,
- Spring Boot 2
- PostgreSQL

#### **PHEBE**

Client: THALES GROUP

Description: Local web app displaying military data from Excel file

#### Achievement:

- Convert .xlsx data into .json
- o Display adaptive graph and tables from .json

Tech Stack:

- o Java 8
- Apache POI for parsing .xlsx
- o JS:
- React JS
- Vis.js a chart library
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- o Java
- React
- Spring
- MySQL
- MongoDB

### Ingénieur logiciels junior, ALTER SOLUTIONS

Nov, 2017 - Dec, 2018 1 year 1 month

PECC:

Client: Sodexo

Description: E-commerce Management App for Business work councils (E-voucher, discount)

Achievement: Added Features and Maintenance

Tech Stack:

- Java 8 => API REST avec Spring Boot 2:
  - Word files manipulation
  - File I/O manipulation
  - ORM JPA
  - LDAP User Management avec JWT
- Javascript => Frontend avec Angular 2
- Database MariaDB

#### **CALIBRATION:**

Client: PSA

Description: Online tool to parse automobile file format (.a2l and .hex, .ulp)

Achievement: Add an web API to parse uploaded files and provide a readable json response

Tech Stack:

- Java 8 => API REST with Spring Boot 2:
- String manipulation (RegEx)

- Byte and Hexadecimal manipulation
- File I/O manipulation
- o Thread manipulation
- Javascript => Frontend avec Angular 2
- o PHP => Back-end (user management, ...) avec Laravel 5
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Java
- Angular
- Spring
- MySQL

### Consultant Junior en développement logiciel, Capgemini

Feb. 2017 - Nov. 2017 9 months

Projet Félix (Facturation ÉLIgible cordaptiX) pour le client EDF/ErDF.

Felix = Progiciel de Facturation d'Électricité et de Gaz pour les professionnels

Projet Félix pour le client EDF:

- Membre d'une équipe Agile(Scrum, XP) :
  - Développement de composants spécifiques dans le cadre du Framework CCnB:
  - Java (Maven, Hibernate, ...)
  - о С,
  - o COBOL.
  - INFORMATICA
  - Mise en place de Tests Unitaires et d'Acceptance
    - Participation au Projet
  - Maintenance de la Plateforme d'Intégration Continu(Fitnesse, Jenkins, ...)
  - Participation au Backlog DevOps Projet
  - Java
  - PostgreSQL
  - o Kafka

#### Assistant Administrateur Système et Réseaux dans le cadre de l'ISO 27001, Gfi Informatique

Sep, 2015 - Jan, 2016 4 months

- Mise en place de l'ITSM avec fonction de Ticketing, iTop :
  - Remplissage de la CMDB grâce à des nombreuses solutions (OCS Inventory, protocole LDAP, Scripting Bash et PHP, Création de Classes PHP pour BDD OQL, ...)
  - Etablissement d'une politique de Help Desk via l'interface ticketing d'iTop (contrat client, modèle de support, SLAs, SLTs, ...)
  - o Configuration de l'outil (Création de modules, intégration de l'outil OCS dans les pages web iTop, ...)
- Administration Systèmes et Réseaux :
  - Implantation d'un serveur de Logs centralisé du parc serveurs (logrotate pour serveurs Linux et Windows)
  - o Changement de la PABX à la VOIP dans tout le site de Douai
  - Création et manipulation de VM à l'aide de VMWare pour la mise en place des serveurs iTop, OCS inventory, serveur de Logs et serveur de production.
  - Mission de HelpDesk

- Réalisation d'un intranet avec fonctionnalités (bibliothèque interactive, vidéothèque et audio-thèque, planning...) à l'aide de PHP/MySQL
- Conception d'affiches et flyers pour la promotion d'événements (Adobe Photoshop CS6)
- Amélioration du site web et des réseaux sociaux (WordPress, Wix)

### Assistant Administrateur Système et Réseaux dans le cadre de Supervision Réseau, Université de Lille 2

May, 2014 - Jul, 2014 2 months

- Etablissement d'un réseau LAN (configuration de matériel Cisco)
- Implémentation de traps SNMP dans le réseau avec alertes mails grâce à des scripts Bash
- Installation et configuration de Suricata outil de Supervision de paquets
- Inventory de Réseaux à l'aide de scripts Bash et du logiciel N-map

### Stage de Gestion, OGEC des Hauts de Lys

Aug, 2013 - Oct, 2013 2 months

Mise en pratique des connaissances acquises en comptabilité/gestion. J'ai pu m'occuper, avec l'aide d'un agent comptable, de la facturation de cet ensemble scolaire privé. Cela m'a permis d'acquérir une certaine organisation et une expérience du travail en groupe.

#### Stage de Vente, NORAUTO

Feb, 2012 - Apr, 2012 2 months

Ce stage de 2 mois a été, pour moi, ma première réelle expérience dans le milieu de l'entreprise. En effet, ce stage m'a permis de mieux comprendre le fonctionnement d'une entreprise et surtout d'y prendre part en tant que vendeur.

### Stage de réparation de matériel informatique, Igraa Informatique

May, 2008 - May, 2008 1 day

Entreprise de vente de pièces détachées et de réparation d'ordinateurs.

Lors de ce stage, j'ai du réparer des micro-ordinateurs ce qui m'a appris beaucoup sur l'assemblage d'ordinateur et ses composants.

J'ai surtout mieux compris le fonctionnement et l'organisation d'une P.M.E.

### **SKILLS**

Pack Office	
Open Office	
C++ Language	
HTML 5	
PHP	
MySQL	
C	

Bash
JavaScript
Ajax
Symfony
Méthodes agiles
Gestion de projet
Design Pattern
VHDL
Microsoft Excel
EDUCATION
Ingénierie logicielle, Diplôme d'ingénieur, Telecom Lille 1 - Ecole d'Ingénieurs Dec, 2012 - Dec, 2017
Scientifique, Baccalauréat, Lycée Faidherbe Dec, 2011 - Dec, 2012
AWARDS

Prix "Entreprise du Futur" du Challenge Entreprendre , Telecom Lille, prix et récompense décernée par Thalès

Awarded on: Feb 28, 2016

